<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.10.xsd" version="0.10" xml:lang="en">
  <siteinfo>
    <sitename>PlayerMadeQuests Wiki</sitename>
    <dbname>bitnami_mediawiki</dbname>
    <base>http://23.23.197.136/wiki/PlayerMadeQuests</base>
    <generator>MediaWiki 1.34.2</generator>
    <case>first-letter</case>
    <namespaces>
      <namespace key="-2" case="first-letter">Media</namespace>
      <namespace key="-1" case="first-letter">Special</namespace>
      <namespace key="0" case="first-letter" />
      <namespace key="1" case="first-letter">Talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="2" case="first-letter">User</namespace>
      <namespace key="3" case="first-letter">User talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="4" case="first-letter">PMQ</namespace>
      <namespace key="5" case="first-letter">PMQ talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="6" case="first-letter">File</namespace>
      <namespace key="7" case="first-letter">File talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="8" case="first-letter">MediaWiki</namespace>
      <namespace key="9" case="first-letter">MediaWiki talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="10" case="first-letter">Template</namespace>
      <namespace key="11" case="first-letter">Template talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="12" case="first-letter">Help</namespace>
      <namespace key="13" case="first-letter">Help talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="14" case="first-letter">Category</namespace>
      <namespace key="15" case="first-letter">Category talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="100" case="first-letter">News</namespace>
      <namespace key="101" case="first-letter">News talk</namespace>
    </namespaces>
  </siteinfo>
  <page>
    <title>Aura</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>46</id>
    <revision>
      <id>263</id>
      <parentid>225</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-02-06T19:20:43Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>100.7.77.237</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Supported objectives */</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1378">The **aura** parameter allows you to specify any aura (buff or debuff) that the player must have in order to trigger an objective.

### Value type

* String - the name of the aura as it appears in-game

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[cast-spell]]
| The aura you must have when casting the spell
|-
| [[equip-item]]
| The aura you must have when equipping the item
|-
| [[explore]]
| The aura you must have when entering the area to be explored
|-
| [[gain-aura]]
| The aura you must gain
|-
| [[kill]]
| The aura you must have when killing the target enemy
|-
| [[loot-item]]
| The aura you must have when looting an item
|-
| [[say]]
| The aura you must have when saying the message
|-
| [[talk-to]]
| The aura you must have when talking to the target NPC
|-
| [[use-emote]]
| The aura you must have when performing the emote
|}

### Usage notes

* The aura's name must be spelled and capitalized exactly as it is in-game in order for the objective to progress.
* Currently, there is no localization implemented in the addon, so players using a client in a different language (where the aura has a different name) will not be able to progress the objective. The initial release of PMQ is targeting English-language clients only, with localization to come later.

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>d2rnc3hsp2duhs0becntxiwh4vfsq8d</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Cache</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>114</id>
    <redirect title="Save Data &amp; Cache" />
    <revision>
      <id>283</id>
      <timestamp>2021-07-24T18:45:27Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Redirected page to [[Save Data &amp; Cache]]</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="31">#REDIRECT [[Save Data &amp; Cache]]</text>
      <sha1>avcyz0hkxlj46e0gn3r48xzf8t17qmm</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Cast-spell</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>105</id>
    <revision>
      <id>294</id>
      <parentid>270</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-07-24T20:31:39Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="2632">The **cast-spell** objective is triggered whenever the player successfully casts a spell. It will not be triggered when a spell or action fails or is interrupted.

This objective is not limited to just magical spells; it can be invoked by a variety of in-game actions related to abilities, items, or interactions within the world. PMQ includes features to help you find the right names and IDs for spells in the game - see the [[spell]] condition page for more information.

### Shorthand

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  # Generic
  - cast-spell goal "spell*" "target"
  # Working examples
  - cast-spell Frostbolt                    # Cast Frostbolt (any rank)
  - cast-spell 3 "Fire Blast"               # Cast Fire Blast 3 times
  - cast-spell 5 Frostbolt "Stonetusk Boar" # Cast Frostbolt on 3 different Stonetusk Boars
}}

### Long form

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - cast-spell:
      spell: Arcane Intellect # Required
      goal: 3
      target: Mangy Wolf
      level: 30
      guild: Pals for Life
      class: Mage
      faction: Alliance
      sametarget: true
      zone: Elwynn Forest
      subzone: Goldshire
      coords: 42.41, 64.47, 0.3
      aura: "Power Word: Fortitude"
      equip: Apprentice's Robe
      item: Light Leather
      text: "Custom display text"
}}

*&lt;nowiki&gt;*required&lt;/nowiki&gt;*

### Supported parameters

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Parameter
! How it's used
|-
| [[aura]]
| The name of the aura you must have when casting the spell
|-
| [[class]]
| The spellcast target must be a player of this class
|-
| [[equip]]
| The name of the item you must have equipped when casting the spell
|-
| [[faction]]
| The spellcast target must be a player or NPC of this faction (Alliance or Horde)
|-
| [[goal]]
| The number of times you must cast the spell
|-
| [[guild]]
| The spellcast target must be a player in this guild
|-
| [[item]]
| The name of the item you must have in your bags when casting the spell
|-
| [[level]]
| The spellcast target must be this level or higher
|-
| **sametarget**
| If true, then multiple casts on the same target will count toward the objective (default: false)
|-
| [[spell]]
| The name or ID of the spell you must cast
|-
| [[target]]
| The name of the target you must cast the spell on
|-
| [[Display Text|text]]
| Custom display text for this objective
|-
| [[zone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[zone|subzone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[coords]]
| The location you must be in when casting the spell
|}

### Usage notes

* This objective relies on caching player/NPC data while you're playing the game. For more information, see [[Save Data &amp; Cache]].

[[Category:Quest Objectives]]</text>
      <sha1>sca5tmx38igt72shx67jcuvm6vzqz55</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Channel</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>92</id>
    <revision>
      <id>217</id>
      <timestamp>2020-12-01T00:43:46Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Created page with "The **channel** parameter allows you to specify the channel through which a [[message]] must be sent in order to satisfy an objective.  ### Value type  * String - the na..."</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="906">The **channel** parameter allows you to specify the channel through which a [[message]] must be sent in order to satisfy an objective.

### Value type

* String - the name of the channel. The following values are supported:
** say
** yell
** guild
** raid
** party
** whisper

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[say]]
| The channel(s) in which you can send the message to complete the objective
|}

### Usage notes

* The value for channel is case-insensitive, meaning both "yell" and "YELL" will work.
* You can specify multiple channels, which means that sending the message in *any one* of these channels will satisfy the objective. For example:

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - say:
      message: "wash yer back"
      channel: [ say, yell ] # You can either /say or /yell this message
}}

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>2r1gmbs036dvx4i01ffb7jbuxn66cb0</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Class</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>111</id>
    <revision>
      <id>280</id>
      <parentid>276</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-07-24T18:42:15Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="777">The **class** parameter allows you to specify the class that a player target must be in order to complete an objective.

### Value type

* String - the name of a playable class

The following class values are supported for TBC:

* Druid
* Hunter
* Mage
* Paladin
* Priest
* Rogue
* Shaman
* Warlock
* Warrior

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[cast-spell]]
| The spellcast target must be a player of this class
|-
| [[kill]]
| The kill target must be a player of this class
|-
| [[use-emote]]
| The emote target must be a player of this class
|}

This parameter can also be used as a [[Requirements|quest requirement or recommendation]].

### Usage notes

* TBD

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>0uz6ehj3mmccbrv02goggxf264c3251</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Configuration</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>55</id>
    <revision>
      <id>256</id>
      <parentid>167</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-01-23T20:13:42Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="4005">[[File:config-menu.png|thumb|The configuration menu in-game]]

This page outlines the settings you can configure in PMQ.

### Notes

* Settings outlined in gray are set to PMQ's default values, while settings in yellow have been modified by the player. You can reset individual settings or all settings using the buttons in the Configuration menu.
* All settings are currently character-bound, not account-bound.
* You must &lt;code&gt;/reload&lt;/code&gt; your UI in order for (most) configuration changes to take effect. This may change in a future release, but for now the settings are fixed in place when the addon loads.
* There are plans for a more robust configuration UI to be developed in the future. However, for now this is the quickest way to add new settings without adding additional UI work.

### Settings

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Setting
! Expected Value
! Description
|-
| ENABLE_GUI
| true, false
| If false, some GUI elements will not be created on startup. Use for troubleshooting only.
|-
| ENABLE_SELF_MESSAGING
| true, false
| If true, any outgoing messages (such as quest sharing) will be redirected back to you with the player name "*yourself*". Use for testing only.
|-
| ENABLE_TRANSACTION_LOGS
| true, false
| If true, will output additional logging for Repository transactions. &lt;br/&gt;You will also need to lower the logging level of the appropriate logger(s) to "trace" in the Logging settings. (extremely verbose, enable for debugging only)
|-
| FEATURE_PET_KILLS
| true, false
| If true, additional checks will be performed to count your pet's contribution toward any [[kill]] objective.
|-
| FILTER_OFFLINE_MESSAGE
| true, false
| PMQ needs to put a special chat filter in place to hide all messages that say &lt;code&gt;No player named '*' is currently playing.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;If this causes you trouble for some reason, change this setting to false to disable that filter.
|-
| GLOBAL_LOG_FILTER
| silent, fatal, error, info, debug, trace
| Indicates the lowest level of log that should be output to the game console by default. Logging can be further configured in the Logging menu.
|-
| ITEM_SCAN_LOG_INTERVAL
| # items/message
| How often the addon should inform you of item scanning progress. A lower number will print chat messages more often.
|-
| ITEM_SCAN_TIMEOUT
| # seconds
| How long to wait for the server to response when scanning for items. A lower number will scan faster, but could miss items.
|-
| NOTIFY_COMPLETE_AUTHOR
| true, false
| If true, you will be notified when any player completes a quest that you wrote.
|-
| NOTIFY_COMPLETE_BULK
| true, false
| If true, you will be notified when any player in your party or raid completes a PMQ quest.
|-
| NOTIFY_COMPLETE_SHARER
| true, false
| If true, you will be notified when any player completes a quest that you shared with them.
|-
| NOTIFY_VERSION_UPDATE
| true, false
| If true, you will be notified once per game session when there is a known PMQ update available.
|-
| PLAYER_LOCATION_INTERVAL
| # of seconds
| Indicates how frequently the addon should check your location when required for [[coords]] conditions.
|-
| PLAYER_LOCATION_TTL
| # of seconds
| Indicates how long the addon should cache your position in game before checking again.
|-
| SPELL_SCAN_INTENSITY
| # spells/frame
| How many spells to scan for on each frame when scanning for spells. A higher number will scan faster, but will hurt game performance.
|-
| SPELL_SCAN_LOG_INTERVAL
| # spells/message
| How often the addon should inform you of spell scanning progress. A lower number will print chat messages more often.
|-
| START_MENU
| menu ID
| Specify a menu to open when the addon loads. Useful for GUI development. Get the menu IDs from the value properties in [https://github.com/runeberry/PlayerMadeQuests/blob/master/src/gui/MainMenu.lua#L10 MainMenu.lua].
|-
| VERSION_INFO_TTL
| # of seconds
| Indicates how long PMQ should remember that addon versions are available and to prompt you to update. (default is 3 days)
|}</text>
      <sha1>79c7aj6l7vnztf8vij4e88kog8kmbjq</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Coords</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>14</id>
    <revision>
      <id>230</id>
      <parentid>161</parentid>
      <timestamp>2020-12-01T03:24:52Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Supported objectives */</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="3613">The **coords** parameter allow you to specify the &lt;code&gt;x,y&lt;/code&gt; coordinates that need to be visited within a zone, as well as the &lt;code&gt;radius&lt;/code&gt; you must be from those coordinates in order to progress an objective.

### Value type

* String - The **coords** value is expressed as a comma-separated string that is parsed into &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;radius&lt;/code&gt; values at runtime. The values must be in the following ranges:
* &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; must be between 0.00 and 100.00, representing coordinate values on the map
* &lt;code&gt;radius&lt;/code&gt; must be between 0.00 and 100.00, representing a distance in coordinate units - **not yards!** PMQ will use a default radius of 0.5 units if no radius is specified.

See the following examples showing how **coords** can be written.

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - explore:
      zone: Elwynn Forest
      coords: 38,72               # Coordinates can be whole numbers
  - explore:
      zone: Elwynn Forest
      coords: 38.51,72.64         # Or you can get precise with decimals
  - explore:
      zone: Elwynn Forest
      coords: 38.51,72.64,0.8     # You can add a custom radius, too
  - explore:
      zone: Elwynn Forest
      coords: 38.51, 72.64, 0.8   # A little space is fine, as a treat
}}

Note that when using **coords** in a shorthand objective, the string must not contain any spaces. However, if you want to include spaces, you can do so safely by wrapping the value in quotes.

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - explore Durotar 22.1,47.6          # OK
  - explore Durotar 22.1,47.6,0.25     # OK
  - explore Durotar 22.1, 47.6, 0.25   # Not OK! Coords will get broken apart
  - explore Durotar '22.1, 47.6, 0.25' # OK (either double or single quotes)
  - explore 'Elwynn Forest'            # Same rule applies to 'zone'
}}

Here's a practical example explained. Given the following objective:

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - explore:
      zone: Elwynn Forest
      coords: 38.2, 47.5, 1
}}

The player must enter the box bounded by the top-left coordinate (37.2, 46.5) and the bottom-right coordinate (39.2, 48.5) in [https://wow.gamepedia.com/Elwynn_Forest Elwynn Forest] order to complete the objective.

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[equip-item]]
| The coordinates you must be near when equipping the item
|-
| [[explore]]
| The coordinates you must be near in order to complete the objective
|-
| [[gain-aura]]
| The coordinates where you must gain the aura
|-
| [[kill]]
| The coordinates where you must kill the target
|-
| [[loot-item]]
| The coordinates where you must loot the item
|-
| [[say]]
| The coordinates where you must say the message
|-
| [[talk-to]]
| The coordinates where you must talk to the target
|-
| [[use-emote]]
| The coordinates where you must use the emote
|}

This parameter can also be used as a [[Start &amp; Complete Objectives|start or complete condition]].

### Usage notes

* A distance of one "coordinate value" is vastly different between zones, since all map coordinates are normalized to 100 x 100 units. This means that a radius of 0.5 units is much larger in the Barrens compared to Deadwind Pass, since the Barrens is a much larger map.
* The coordinates + radius currently form a square in which the player must explore. This may change to a circle in a future release.
* Unfortunately, the WoW client does not expose a way to read a player's &lt;code&gt;z&lt;/code&gt; (height) coordinate, so it is not possible to include this in the **coords** parameter.

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>lsy7bjp4h6s9sm4xmsgggxd5xy2te4g</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Display Text</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>18</id>
    <revision>
      <id>267</id>
      <parentid>232</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-02-06T19:22:19Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>100.7.77.237</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Supported objectives */</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="4963">The **text** parameter allows you to precisely define how your quest information will be displayed when it's presented to players. PMQ will automatically generate text for your quest objectives, requirements, and more based on the information that you provide, but overriding this with the **text** parameter will allow you to give your quests a little more personality beyond the standard text.

### Value type

* String or table - you can specify a single text string that will be used for all use cases, or you can specify different strings for each use case. See the examples below.

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[cast-spell]]
| Custom display text
|-
| [[equip-item]]
| Custom display text
|-
| [[gain-aura]]
| Custom display text
|-
| [[explore]]
| Custom display text
|-
| [[kill]]
| Custom display text
|-
| [[loot-item]]
| Custom display text
|-
| [[say]]
| Custom display text
|-
| [[talk-to]]
| Custom display text
|-
| [[use-emote]]
| Custom display text
|}

Custom display text can also be used with a [[Start &amp; Complete Objectives|start and complete conditions]] as well as [[Requirements|quest requirements]].

### Usage notes

{{code-yaml|c=
start:
  zone: Azshara
  text: Go to the treacherous cliffs north of Orgrimmar to begin this quest.
}}

With the above configuration, your custom text will be displayed wherever PMQ displays information about the &lt;code&gt;start&lt;/code&gt; objective for a quest.

You can take this a step further and specify different text for different contexts within PMQ. See the following example:

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - explore:
      zone: Azshara
      x: 38.9
      y: 47.2
      text:
        log: Go to the secret spot
        progress: Secret spot uncovered
        quest: Find the hero's secret spot in %z
}}

With this configuration, you will see different custom text displayed in the quest log, progress message, and quest info frame, instead of the same line of text for all 3 cases. Any cases not specified under &lt;code&gt;text&lt;/code&gt; will fall back on the default display text provided by PMQ.

You may also notice the use of &lt;code&gt;%z&lt;/code&gt; in the text above. This will get populated with the value of &lt;code&gt;zone&lt;/code&gt; when the text is displayed. Each objective supports a set of these variables for custom text to reduce the amount of repetition in your script - these variables are listed below.

### Display text variables

You can use special variables in your display text string to show the value of different parameters for that objective.

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! colspan=2|Parameter values
|-
| **%a**
| [[aura]]
|-
| **%co**
| [[coords]]
|-
| **%ch**
| [[channel]]
|-
| **%e**
| [[equip]]
|-
| **%em**
| [[emote]]
|-
| **%g**
| [[goal]]
|-
| **%i**
| [[item]]
|-
| **%lang**
| [[language]]
|-
| **%msg**
| [[message]]
|-
| **%p**
| [[goal|progress]]
|-
| **%t**
| [[target]] or [[recipient]]
|-
| **%sz**
| [[zone|subzone]]
|-
| **%z**
| [[zone]]
|-
! colspan=2|Derived Values
|-
| **%g2**
| prints **goal** only if goal &gt; 1
|-
| **%p2**
| prints **progress** only if progress &lt; goal
|-
| **%r**
| radius of **coords**
|-
| **%x**
| x-coordinate of **coords**
|-
| **%xy**
| **coords** formatted as: &lt;code&gt;(x, y)&lt;/code&gt;
|-
| **%xyr**
| **coords** formatted as: &lt;code&gt;(x, y) +/- radius&lt;/code&gt;
|-
| **%xyz**
| location formatted as: &lt;code&gt;(x, y) in zone in subzone&lt;/code&gt;
|-
| **%y**
| y-coordinate of **coords**
|-
| **%z2**
| location formatted as: &lt;code&gt;zone in subzone&lt;/code&gt;
|}

### Quest-level variables

The following variables can be used in the quest's &lt;code&gt;description&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;completion&lt;/code&gt; fields to provide some dynamic flair to your quest text. The Player Info variables will change based on the player who's currently playing the quest.

The &lt;code&gt;%gen&lt;/code&gt; variable is intended to be used as a flag that can result in different text depending on the player's gender. See how it's used in this example:

{{code-yaml|c=
quest:
  name: Joining the Team
  description: So you're the infamous %name, huh? Aren't you kinda short for a %race?
  completion: Well I'll be, you actually did it! Not bad for a %class. Glad to have a [%gen:guy{{!}}gal] like you on our team.
}}

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! colspan=2|Player Info
|-
| **%name**
| The player's name
|-
| **%class**
| The player's class (e.g. "Mage")
|-
| **%race**
| The player's race (e.g. "Tauren")
|-
| **%gen**
| The player's gender flag (see example above)
|-
! colspan=2|Quest Info
|-
| **%author**
| The name of the player who wrote the quest
|-
| **%giver**
| The name of the player who shared the quest (changes every time the quest is shared)
|-
! colspan=2|Formatting
|-
| **%n**
| newline for [[YAML|long strings]]
|-
| **%br**
| line-break (double newline) for [[YAML|long strings]]
|}

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>tcaybg2ql6tgwlt9aitg0w8yzxspqtf</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Emote</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>15</id>
    <revision>
      <id>133</id>
      <parentid>101</parentid>
      <timestamp>2020-08-12T23:26:29Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="655">The **emote** parameter is only available for use with the [[use-emote]] objective. It allows you to specify which emote should trigger the objective.

### Value type

* String - the name of the emote to use, without the slash

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[use-emote]]
| The name of the emote to use
|}

### Usage notes

* Any emotes that cause the same chat message will all be able to trigger the objective. For example, if the emote parameter is "laugh", then both &lt;code&gt;/laugh&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/lol&lt;/code&gt; will satisfy the objective.

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>oirxuywdb34dx13v3mlho5v5t4j7hvn</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Equip</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>53</id>
    <revision>
      <id>264</id>
      <parentid>227</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-02-06T19:21:27Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>100.7.77.237</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Supported objectives */</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1346">The **equip** parameter allows you to specify an item that the player must have equipped order to complete an objective.

### Value type

* String - the name of the item as it appears in-game

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[cast-spell]]
| The item you must have equipped when casting the spell
|-
| [[equip-item]]
| The item you must equip to complete the objective
|-
| [[explore]]
| An item you must have equipped when entering the area to be explored
|-
| [[gain-aura]]
| An item you must have equipped when gaining the aura
|-
| [[kill]]
| An item you must have equipped when killing the target enemy
|-
| [[loot-item]]
| An item you must have equipped when looting the target item
|-
| [[say]]
| An item you must have equipped when saying the message
|-
| [[talk-to]]
| An item you must have equipped when talking to the target NPC
|-
| [[use-emote]]
| An item you must have equipped when using the emote
|}

### Usage notes

* Currently, there is no localization implemented in the addon, so players using a client in a different language (where the item has a different name) will not be able to progress the objective. The initial release of PMQ is targeting English-language clients only, with localization to come later.

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>nb96bhs2aai9ctg05myayngy9e36r29</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Equip-item</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>51</id>
    <revision>
      <id>138</id>
      <timestamp>2020-08-24T00:25:38Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Created page with "The **equip-item** objective is triggered whenever you equip an item.  ### Shorthand  {{code-yaml|c= objectives:   - equip-item "equip*" }}  ''&lt;nowiki&gt;*required&lt;/nowiki&gt;..."</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="981">The **equip-item** objective is triggered whenever you equip an item.

### Shorthand

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - equip-item "equip*"
}}

*&lt;nowiki&gt;*required&lt;/nowiki&gt;*

### Long form

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - equip-item:
      equip: Loose Chain Mail # Required
      aura: "Power Word: Fortitude"
      item: Light Leather
      zone: Elwynn Forest
      subzone: Goldshire
      coords: 42.41, 64.47, 0.3
      text: "Custom display text"
}}

### Supported parameters

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Parameter
! How it's used
|-
| [[aura]]
| The name of the aura you must have when equipping the item
|-
| [[equip]]
| The name of the item you must equip
|-
| [[item]]
| The name of another item you must have in your bags when you equip this item
|-
| [[Display Text|text]]
| Custom display text for this objective
|-
| [[zone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[zone|subzone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[coords]]
| The location you must be in when equipping this item
|}

[[Category:Quest Objectives]]</text>
      <sha1>tev9li190rcrstm795hw8jbpye3rn9v</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Explore</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>21</id>
    <revision>
      <id>142</id>
      <parentid>123</parentid>
      <timestamp>2020-08-24T00:37:05Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1384">The **explore** objective is used to direct a player to go to a specific area for a quest. This objective is triggered whenever you change zones or subzones.

When you enter a zone or subzone in which you have an objective to explore certain coordinates, PMQ will begin polling on an interval to see if you're within the designated radius of those coordinates. PMQ will stop polling for your location when you leave the area of that objective or complete that objective.

### Shorthand

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - explore "zone*" "coords"
}}

*&lt;nowiki&gt;*required&lt;/nowiki&gt;*

### Long form

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - explore:
      zone: Elwynn Forest # Required
      subzone: Goldshire
      coords: 42.41, 64.47, 0.3
      aura: "Power Word: Fortitude"
      equip: Loose Chain Mail
      item: Light Leather
      text: "Custom display text"
}}

### Supported parameters

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Parameter
! How it's used
|-
| [[aura]]
| The aura you must have when exploring this area
|-
| [[equip]]
| An item you must have equipped when exploring this area
|-
| [[item]]
| An item you must have in your bags when exploring this area
|-
| [[Display Text|text]]
| Custom display text for this objective
|-
| [[zone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[zone|subzone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[coords]]
| The location that must be visited to complete this objective
|}

[[Category:Quest Objectives]]</text>
      <sha1>kgdjr5rb017778dozs9en7ixzf3zgvy</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Faction</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>112</id>
    <revision>
      <id>281</id>
      <parentid>277</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-07-24T18:42:23Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="721">The **faction** parameter allows you to specify that a target player or NPC must be a member of either the Alliance or the Horde in order to complete an objective.

### Value type

* String - either **Alliance** or **Horde**

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[cast-spell]]
| The spellcast target must be a player or NPC of this faction
|-
| [[kill]]
| The kill target must be a player or NPC of this faction
|-
| [[use-emote]]
| The emote target must be a player or NPC of this faction
|}

This parameter can also be used as a [[Requirements|quest requirement or recommendation]].

### Usage notes

* TBD

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>ospwy1by3q0wzzw83704taq2u6skrsn</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Gain-aura</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>45</id>
    <revision>
      <id>143</id>
      <parentid>124</parentid>
      <timestamp>2020-08-24T00:38:44Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="984">The **gain-aura** objective is triggered whenever you gain a buff or debuff.

### Shorthand

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - gain-aura "aura*"
}}

*&lt;nowiki&gt;*required&lt;/nowiki&gt;*

### Long form

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - gain-aura:
      aura: "Power Word: Fortitude" # Required
      equip: Loose Chain Mail
      item: Light Leather
      zone: Elwynn Forest
      subzone: Goldshire
      coords: 42.41, 64.47, 0.3
      text: "Custom display text"
}}

### Supported parameters

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Parameter
! How it's used
|-
| [[aura]]
| The name of the aura you must gain to complete this objective
|-
| [[equip]]
| An item you must have equipped when gaining this aura
|-
| [[item]]
| An item you must have in your bags when gaining this aura
|-
| [[Display Text|text]]
| Custom display text for this objective
|-
| [[zone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[zone|subzone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[coords]]
| The location you must be in when gaining the aura
|}

[[Category:Quest Objectives]]</text>
      <sha1>g71x965903549id8wb92xjhezay3w4x</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Goal</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>16</id>
    <revision>
      <id>265</id>
      <parentid>157</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-02-06T19:21:45Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>100.7.77.237</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Supported objectives */</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1098">The **goal** parameter is available to most objectives to specify how many times that objective must be triggered in order to be marked "complete". For example, in the objective "kill 5 Chicken", &lt;code&gt;5&lt;/code&gt; is considered the goal.

Some objectives do not support a goal parameter because it doesn't make sense to complete them more than once in the same quest. For example, the **explore** objective does not support a goal - why would you need to explore the same area twice?

### Value type

* Number - must be a whole number greater than 0

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[cast-spell]]
| The number of times you must cast the spell
|-
| [[kill]]
| The number of times the target must be killed
|-
| [[loot-item]]
| The number of items you must loot
|-
| [[talk-to]]
| The number of times the target must be talked to
|-
| [[use-emote]]
| The number of times the emote must be used
|}

### Usage notes

* When a goal is not specified on an objective, it always defaults to 1.

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>gtw74kp24eun0mmkp9xx117x3gpv4t8</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Guides/Writing Quests</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>10</id>
    <revision>
      <id>60</id>
      <parentid>49</parentid>
      <timestamp>2020-08-08T19:03:29Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="4547">## How quests are played in PMQ

PMQ was designed to emulate the look and feel of WoW: Classic quests as closely as possible, while still offering enough features and flexibility for players to design truly unique quests that stand apart from those in game. So if you've ever done any questing in WoW: Classic, you will quickly understand how quests are played in PMQ.

That said, there are some differences between PMQ and WoW that you will likely encounter. Let's go over the general gameplay loop for PMQ quests:

# **Accepting a quest.** You'll be prompted to start a quest when another character shares one with you, when you're testing out a draft that you've written, or when you want to play one of the demo quests packaged with PMQ. Many quests can be started anywhere in the world by any character, but some quests may have additional restrictions:
#* Quests can have additional **[[Requirements]]** you will need to meet in order to accept the quest, such as level or class requirements.
#* Quests may require you to be in a certain area, near a certain NPC or meet some other **[[Start &amp; Complete Objectives|start condition]]** in order to accept the quest.
# **Completing objectives.** Most quests will have one or more **[[Objective|Objectives]]** to complete. Objectives can include killing monsters, talking to NPCs, exploring areas, and much more. Some objectives only need to be completed once, such as exploring an area. But other objectives must be completed multiple times, such as killing 5 of a monster. This number is known as the **[[Goal]]** for this objective, and the objective is considered complete when your **progress** is greater than or equal to the goal.
# **Turning in a quest.** After you've completed all objectives for a quest, the quest itself is considered complete. But you will still need to turn in the quest to consider it "finished". Like when accepting a quest, many quests can be finished anywhere at anytime, but some quests may impose additional rules:
#* Quests may require you to be in a certain area, near a certain NPC or meet some other **[[Start &amp; Complete Objectives|complete condition]]** in order to finish the quest.

## How to write quests

[[File:ogre1.png|thumb|Example rendering of the **start** block and quest **description** text]]
[[File:ogre2.png|thumb|Example rendering of the **complete** block and quest **completion** text]]

PMQ quests are written in-game with a short YAML script. If you're not familiar with YAML, consider reading up on this short [[Guides/YAML Crash Course|YAML Crash Course]] to learn everything you need to know for writing quests in PMQ. If you're comfortable writing simple macros in WoW, then you should have no problem picking up the basics of YAML.

When you're ready to start writing your own quests, start by checking out the **Demo Quests** provided by PMQ (Main Menu &gt; Quests &gt; Demo Quests). You can view the code used write these demos, and you can even copy them directly to your Drafts and start modifying them yourself.

You can also create a new quest from scratch by going to the **My Drafts** menu and selecting New. Be sure to **Save** your changes often, and click **Validate** to see if your quest can be played as it's written. You can start playing your custom quest by selecting the quest, then clicking **Start Quest** on the My Drafts menu.

Ready to learn more? Or just want to see all the options available for PMQ quests? Check out the following guides:

* [[Requirements|Quest recommendations &amp; requirements]]
* [[Start &amp; Complete Objectives|Quest start &amp; complete conditions]]
* [[Objective|Quest objectives]]

Here's an example of what a fully-featured quest might look like:

{{code-yaml|c=
quest:
  name: It's All Ogre Now
  description: &gt;
    Look kid, I ain't got time to explain. The ogres got somethin'
    dangerous and they're comin' after me with it. I need you distract
    'em for a bit, then wait for me at the end of the pier in
    Steamwheedle Port.
  completion: You arrive at the pier, but Marvon is nowhere to be found.
start:
  zone: Tanaris
  target: Marvon Rivetseeker
objectives:
  - explore:
      zone: Eastmoon Ruins
      text: Go to the %z south of Marvon.
  - kill 6 "Dunemaul Ogre Mage"
  - emote roar 4 "Dunemaul Brute"
complete:
  zone: Steamwheedle Port
  coords: 68.24,22.95
}}

Want to see how it works? Feel free to copy-paste this quest into your own draft in-game. Try changing some of the values and see how the quest is changed as a result.</text>
      <sha1>nmircac8djumykbfojcbncw5o8e5hn8</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Guides/YAML Crash Course</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>47</id>
    <redirect title="YAML" />
    <revision>
      <id>105</id>
      <timestamp>2020-08-12T00:21:43Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Dolphinspired moved page [[Guides/YAML Crash Course]] to [[YAML]]: Moving to top-level for visibility</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="18">#REDIRECT [[YAML]]</text>
      <sha1>7rvfkj2m2mz49vwuuasrqbiwwb12dst</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Guild</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>110</id>
    <revision>
      <id>275</id>
      <timestamp>2021-07-24T18:30:31Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Created page with "The **guild** parameter allows you to specify the name of a guild that a target player must be a part of in order to complete an objective.  ### Value type  * String - t..."</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="675">The **guild** parameter allows you to specify the name of a guild that a target player must be a part of in order to complete an objective.

### Value type

* String - the name of the guild.

**Note:** The guild name is case-sensitive and must match exactly as it appears in game, accents and all!

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[cast-spell]]
| The spellcast target must be a player in this guild
|-
| [[kill]]
| The kill target must be a player in this guild
|-
| [[use-emote]]
| The emote target must be a player in this guild
|}

### Usage notes

* TBD

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>tgaeenw6fhijldq08oo4910x112ee9k</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Item</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>52</id>
    <revision>
      <id>266</id>
      <parentid>243</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-02-06T19:22:01Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>100.7.77.237</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Supported objectives */</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1703">{{About|This page refers to items as they are used with [[Objective|quest objectives]]. For items used as quest rewards, see [[Item (Rewards)]].}}

The **item** parameter allows you to specify an item that the player must have in their bags in order to complete an objective.

### Value type

* String - the name of the item as it appears in-game

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[cast-spell]]
| An item you must have in your bags when casting the spell
|-
| [[equip-item]]
| An item you must have in your bags when equipping the item specified with the [[equip]] parameter
|-
| [[explore]]
| An item you must have in your bags when entering the area to be explored
|-
| [[gain-aura]]
| An item you must have in your bags when gaining the aura
|-
| [[kill]]
| An item you must have in your bags when killing the target enemy
|-
| [[loot-item]]
| The item you must loot
|-
| [[say]]
| An item you must have in your bags when saying the message
|-
| [[talk-to]]
| An item you must have in your bags when talking to the target NPC
|-
| [[use-emote]]
| An item you must have in your bags when using the emote
|}

### Usage notes

* It is currently not possible to specify a quantity of an item that the player must have in their bags. However, this is planned for a release in the near future.
* Currently, there is no localization implemented in the addon, so players using a client in a different language (where the item has a different name) will not be able to progress the objective. The initial release of PMQ is targeting English-language clients only, with localization to come later.

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>5y44bc4vedry513mu9l4n1rdul9x3he</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Item (Rewards)</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>102</id>
    <revision>
      <id>249</id>
      <parentid>248</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-01-01T00:56:49Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="3363">{{About|This page refers to items as they are used with [[Rewards|quest rewards]]. For items used in quest objectives, see [[Item]].}}

The **item** parameter of a quest reward allows you to specify one or more items that will be rewarded upon completion of a quest. You can also declare that a player must **choose** one item from the list rather than receive all of them - see [[Rewards]] for more info.

### Value type

* String - the name of the item as it appears in game, along with an optional quantity

{{code-yaml|c=
# Single item
  item: Traveler's Jerkin
# Single item with quantity
  item: 20 Major Mana Potion
# Multiple items
  item:
    - Flimsy Chain Gloves
    - Flimsy Chain Bracers
    - Flimsy Chain Pants
# Multiple items, some with quantity
  item:
    - Flimsy Chain Gloves
    - 5 Minor Healing Potion
    - 10 Minor Mana Potion
}}

* Table - with the either "id" or "name" and, optionally, "quantity"

{{code-yaml|c=
# Single item
  item:
    - id: 19019
# Single item with quantity
  item:
    - name: Nature Protection Potion
      quantity: 5
# Multiple items
  item:
    - id: 2153
    - id: 2154
    - id: 2155
# Multiple items, some with quantity
  item:
    - name: Major Healing Potion
    - name: Major Mana Potion
      quantity: 20
    - id: 2180
      quantity: 5
}}

### Getting items by name

PMQ requires that all item names must be valid in-game item names so that the icon, tooltip, etc. can be retrieving using the WoW API. However, one of the limitation of the WoW API is that some of this information cannot be retrieved by name unless you have **encountered that item during your current game session**, meaning you've seen that item in your bags, bank, etc. PMQ adds an extra layer of functionality so that items that you have encountered will be written to a save file shared by all of your characters - meaning that if you encounter an item once on any character, you can then refer to it by name on all characters as, even between sessions.

But because it's not a perfect system, you may run into issues when trying to set an item reward by name that you don't actually own. There are, however, some ways to work around this:

* If possible, simply obtain the item and hover over it in your bags. You should now be able to refer to this item by name.
* Search for the item on [https://classic.wowhead.com/ Wowhead] and grab the item's ID from the URL, such as &lt;code&gt;item=1234&lt;/code&gt;, where 1234 is the ID. Then, do one of two things:
** Use the item by ID in your quest, following the examples above
** Use the chat command &lt;code&gt;/pmq lookup-item 1234&lt;/code&gt;, where 1234 is your item ID. If this is a valid item ID, then the item will be linked back to you, and you can now refer to this item by name in any quest you write.
* If you want to avoid this problem in the future, run the command &lt;code&gt;/pmq scan-items&lt;/code&gt;. This kicks off a process that will check for **every known item ID in the game** and cache them all for future use in any quest draft on any character. However this takes about 20 minutes to run (for an estimated 25k items in Classic) and will be interrupted if you log out or &lt;code&gt;/reload&lt;/code&gt; your UI. This process is throttled so you won't suffer any performance issues or get kicked offline as a result of scanning for items.

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>5nqnbwupoidd7ryrd9q8ovrxbzobyke</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Kill</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>23</id>
    <revision>
      <id>293</id>
      <parentid>272</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-07-24T20:31:18Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="2105">The **kill** objective is triggered whenever you or someone in your party kills a monster or NPC in combat. Your party must have the tag on an enemy when it dies in order to gain progress.

### Shorthand

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - kill goal "target*"
}}

*&lt;nowiki&gt;*required&lt;/nowiki&gt;*

### Long form

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - kill:
      goal: 3
      target: Mangy Wolf
      level: 30
      guild: Pals for Life
      class: Mage
      faction: Alliance
      zone: Elwynn Forest
      subzone: Goldshire
      coords: 42.41, 64.47, 0.3
      aura: "Power Word: Fortitude"
      equip: Loose Chain Mail
      item: Light Leather
      text: "Custom display text"
}}

### Supported parameters

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Parameter
! How it's used
|-
| [[aura]]
| The name of the aura you must have when killing the target
|-
| [[class]]
| The kill target must be a player of this class
|-
| [[equip]]
| An item you must have equipped when killing the target
|-
| [[faction]]
| The kill target must be a player or NPC of this faction (Alliance or Horde)
|-
| [[goal]]
| The number of enemies to kill
|-
| [[guild]]
| The kill target must be a player in this guild
|-
| [[item]]
| An item you must have in your bags when killing the target
|-
| [[level]]
| The kill target must be this level or higher
|-
| [[target]]
| The name of the NPC or player to kill
|-
| [[Display Text|text]]
| Custom display text for this objective
|-
| [[zone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[zone|subzone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[coords]]
| The location you must be in when killing the target
|}

### Notes

* This objective contains additional logic to count players' pet contributions as kills. In short, when your pet attacks any target, you will get kill credit for that target when it dies. This behavior can be toggled off with the FEATURE_PET_KILLS setting in the [[Configuration]] menu. If this behavior is inaccurate or causing problems, let us known on Discord!
* This objective relies on caching player/NPC data while you're playing the game. For more information, see [[Save Data &amp; Cache]].

[[Category:Quest Objectives]]</text>
      <sha1>90op1kpeynhunpr3vipwdzljeqk47nd</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Language</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>96</id>
    <revision>
      <id>222</id>
      <timestamp>2020-12-01T01:27:48Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Created page with "[[File:Language_select.png|thumb|300px|Left-click the speech bubble to select your spoken language]] File:Language_skill.png|thumb|300px|A character's language skills as lis..."</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1848">[[File:Language_select.png|thumb|300px|Left-click the speech bubble to select your spoken language]]
[[File:Language_skill.png|thumb|300px|A character's language skills as listed in WoW: Classic]]

The **language** parameter allows you to specify a Role-Playing language that a [[message]] must be spoken in when completing an objective.

In order to speak in a special language other than Common (Alliance default) or Orcish (Horde default), you must left-click the chat bubble icon on your chat frame, go to Languages, and select the language you want to speak in. Your character must have proficiency in a language in order to speak it. In WoW: Classic, you can see your character's proficient languages under the Skills tab of the Character Info screen (default hotkey: K).

### Value type

* String - the name of the language as it appears in-game. See the [https://wow.gamepedia.com/Language Language page on Wowpedia] for all available options.

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[say]]
| The language(s) that the message must be spoken in
|}

### Usage notes

* The language value is case-sensitive, meaning that it must matching the casing as it appears in-game. For example, "Dwarvish" will work, but "dwarvish" and "DWARVISH" will not work.
* You cannot whisper another player in a different language, so don't specify a language if the objective's [[channel]] is "whisper", or if you specify a message [[recipient]].
* You can specify multiple languages, which means that sending the message in *any one* of these languages will satisfy the objective. For example:

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - say:
      message: "wash yer back"
      language: [ Dwarvish, Gnomish ] # You can say this in either Dwarvish or Gnomish
}}

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>os94nbmia7jth9qunq4f4x3yguzke2x</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Level</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>109</id>
    <revision>
      <id>279</id>
      <parentid>274</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-07-24T18:41:50Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="731">The **level** parameter allows you to specify the minimum level that a target must be in order to complete an objective.

### Value type

* Number - the minimum level of the target

Currently, this number must be from 1-73 (the maximum visible level for monsters in TBC).

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[cast-spell]]
| The spellcast target must be this level or higher
|-
| [[kill]]
| The kill target must be this level or higher
|-
| [[use-emote]]
| The emote target must be this level or higher
|}

This parameter can also be used as a [[Requirements|quest requirement or recommendation]].

### Usage notes

* TBD

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>i2b4mvgcg5cjzzn38ldx9ywz4xa0239</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Loot-item</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>54</id>
    <revision>
      <id>153</id>
      <parentid>152</parentid>
      <timestamp>2020-09-07T02:42:48Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1265">The **loot-item** objective is triggered whenever you loot an item from any source. Specifically, this is triggered by any event that can write a loot message to the chatbox. This includes:

* Looting items from bodies
* Harvesting items with gathering skills
* Looting items from containers (like lockboxes, world chests)

### Shorthand

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - loot-item goal "item*"
}}

*&lt;nowiki&gt;*required&lt;/nowiki&gt;*

### Long form

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - loot-item:
      item: Light Leather # Required
      goal: 5
      equip: Loose Chain Mail
      aura: "Power Word: Fortitude"
      zone: Elwynn Forest
      subzone: Goldshire
      coords: 42.41, 64.47, 0.3
      text: "Custom display text"
}}

### Supported parameters

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Parameter
! How it's used
|-
| [[aura]]
| The name of the aura you must have when looting
|-
| [[equip]]
| The name of an item you must have equipped when looting
|-
| [[goal]]
| The number of items you must loot
|-
| [[item]]
| The name of the item you must loot
|-
| [[Display Text|text]]
| Custom display text for this objective
|-
| [[zone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[zone|subzone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[coords]]
| The location you must be in when looting this item
|}

[[Category:Quest Objectives]]</text>
      <sha1>dv9vilh05flfnxto94zjtlgqf00qkit</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Lua:Addon functions</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>50</id>
    <revision>
      <id>110</id>
      <parentid>109</parentid>
      <timestamp>2020-08-12T01:12:22Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="554">This is a list of all of the functions available directly on PMQ's &lt;code&gt;addon&lt;/code&gt; object.

TODO: finish this later

{{code-lua|c=
addon:catch(fn, ...)
addon:onload(fn)
addon:load()
addon:OnSaveDataLoaded(fn)
addon:GetPlayerAuras()
addon:GetPlayerAuraNames()
addon:GetPlayerLocation()
addon:CheckPlayerInZone(zone)
addon:StartPollingLocation(id)
addon:StopPollingLocation(id)
addon:StopAllLocationPolling()
addon:PlaySound(name)
addon:IsTargetExcluded(context, targetGuid)
addon:AddTargetExclusion(context, targetGuid)
addon:ClearTargetExclusions()
}}</text>
      <sha1>4tqsjlsquumf1ijbklhvv9lnydqifm0</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Main Page</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>3</id>
    <redirect title="PlayerMadeQuests" />
    <revision>
      <id>5</id>
      <timestamp>2020-08-06T02:32:34Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Dolphinspired moved page [[Main Page]] to [[PlayerMadeQuests]]</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="30">#REDIRECT [[PlayerMadeQuests]]</text>
      <sha1>rb72le3h43sh0xgob2bi64aqrtnkk6e</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Message</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>97</id>
    <revision>
      <id>223</id>
      <timestamp>2020-12-01T02:18:22Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Created page with "The **message** parameter allows you to specify a phrase or pattern that must be spoken by the player in order to complete an objective.  ### Value type  * String - the..."</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="2773">The **message** parameter allows you to specify a phrase or pattern that must be spoken by the player in order to complete an objective.

### Value type

* String - the phrase or pattern that the player must say.

The full range of [https://riptutorial.com/lua/example/20315/lua-pattern-matching Lua patterns] are supported for this parameter, but you can use the following examples to get started.

Note that all values for message are **case-insensitive**, meaning that "happy birthday" and "Happy Birthday" would both work in the first example.

{| class="wikitable"
! Value
! Result
|-
| "happy birthday"
| The message must contain the phrase "happy birthday" somewhere inside it
|-
| "^happy b"
| The message must start with the phrase "happy b"
|-
| "birthday$"
| The message must end with the word "birthday"
|-
| "^happy bar mitzvah!$"
| The message must be exactly the phrase "happy bar mitzvah!" with nothing else before or after it
|}

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[say]]
| The message which the player must say in order to complete the objective
|}

### Usage notes

* While Lua patterns are case-sensitive, the value for this message parameter is intentionally **not case-sensitive**, meaning that you cannot force a player to say something in a specific casing style. For example, if you specify the pattern "Happy Birthday", then a player will be able to say "happy birthday" to satisfy the condition. As such, it's recommended to keep your patterns for message to all lowercase letters, for simplicity.
* It can be somewhat tedious to test complex message patterns in-game, so until there is a better testing method included with PMQ, consider using this [https://rextester.com/l/lua_online_compiler Online Lua Compiler] to test which phrases will or will not work with your message pattern. Simply copy/paste the following code into the editor linked, and click **Run it (F8)** to print the results below the code editor. Of course, you'll want to change out the pattern and chat messages in the below code to suit your needs.

{{code-lua|c=
-- Change this pattern to the "message" pattern value you want to test
local pattern = "nothing %w-, nothing %w-"

local function testPattern(message)
  local result
  if string.match(message, pattern) then
    result = "[PASS]" -- This chat message would pass the objective
  else
    result = "[FAIL]" -- This chat message would NOT pass the objective
  end
  print(result, message)
end

-- Test any chat messages you want to test against the pattern
testPattern("nothing ventured, nothing gained")
testPattern("nothing spent, nothing saved")
testPattern("this message should not pass")
}}

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>mp7dd8lngcfhhmtvdtgrj4bqjfvq50j</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Objective</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>22</id>
    <revision>
      <id>89</id>
      <parentid>70</parentid>
      <timestamp>2020-08-09T00:46:10Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* List of objectives */</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="2193">A quest **objective** is an action you must take in order to make progress toward completing a quest.

## Writing Objectives

[[File:Objectives1.png|thumb|300px|Quest objectives as shown in quest info]]
[[File:QuestLog2.png|thumb|300px|Quest objectives as shown in the quest log]]

All objectives are written under the &lt;code&gt;objectives&lt;/code&gt; property in QuestScript, and each objective must be preceded by a &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt;. Here are some formatting examples:

 OK

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - kill Cow
  - kill 3 Chicken
  - kill 5 "Mangy Wolf"
}}

 Not OK

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
- kill Cow                  # not indented far enough
  -kill 3 Chicken           # no space after dash
    - kill 5 "Mangy Wolf"   # indented too far
}}

### Shorthand

Each objective supports a "shorthand" format, which lets you quickly write an objective with only the most basic parameters in a single line. The parameters supported by the shorthand form are different for each objective.

For example, let's break down the shorthand form of the &lt;code&gt;kill&lt;/code&gt; objective:

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - kill 5 "Mangy Wolf"
}}

When compiled into a quest, this line gets broken apart into the following properties:

* **objective:** kill
* **goal:** 5 *(optional, number of times this objective must be performed)*
* **target:** "Mangy Wolf" *(name of the monster which must be killed)*

Note that multi-word phrases like "Mangy Wolf" must be written with quotes in order to be recognized as a single parameter value in the shorthand form. For single-word phrases, quotes are optional.

The help page for each objective (linked below) will outline the parameters supported by that objective's shorthand form.

### Long-form

If you want to access the full set of parameters for an objective, you can write it out in its complete form, where each parameter of the objective is defined explicitly. For example, the last example would be written in long-form as:

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - kill:
      goal: 5
      target: Mangy Wolf
}}

## List of objectives

You can view a list of all currently supported quest objectives at [[:Category:Quest Objectives]].</text>
      <sha1>ftijp0aq0irsbiun3p7d9ud4tidbm2o</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>PlayerMadeQuests</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>1</id>
    <revision>
      <id>295</id>
      <parentid>261</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-07-24T20:36:12Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="2348">**PlayerMadeQuests (PMQ)** is an addon for [https://worldofwarcraft.com/en-us/wowclassic World of Warcraft: Classic] that allows you to write your own custom quests, play them in-game, and share them with other players.

Ready to try it out? You can get it here:

* Download PMQ from [https://www.curseforge.com/wow/addons/pmq CurseForge] (can be installed through the [https://curseforge.overwolf.com/ CurseForge app])
* Download the latest release in a zip file directly from [https://github.com/runeberry/PlayerMadeQuests/releases Github]

Several playable demo quests are provided with PMQ to help you learn how to write your own quests. Additional help and even more examples can be found on this Wiki.

You can contribute to PMQ by giving us feedback during the Beta Test - join us on [https://discord.gg/gHMjCgs Discord]!

### Latest News

* A new menu has been added to search your **[[Save Data &amp; Cache]]** with v0.6.0-beta (24-Jul-2021)
* New parameters have been added to these objectives with v0.6.0-beta: (24-Jul-2021)
** **[[kill]]** targets by **[[class]]**, **[[faction]]**, **[[guild]]**, or **[[level]]**
** **[[cast-spell]]** on targets by **[[class]]**, **[[faction]]**, **[[guild]]**, or **[[level]]**
** **[[use-emote]]** on targets by **[[class]]**, **[[faction]]**, **[[guild]]**, or **[[level]]**
* The **[[Cast-spell]]** objective has been added in v0.5.0-beta (23-Jan-2021)
* You can now offer **[[Rewards]]** for completing your quests as of v0.4.0-beta (31-Dec-2020)
* The **[[Say]]** objective has been added in v0.3.4-beta (30-Nov-2020)
* **[[:News:The Road Ahead (25-Nov-2020)]]**

### Helpful Pages

* [[Guides/Writing Quests]]
* [[Guides/YAML Crash Course]]
* [[:Category:Quest Objectives|List of all quest objectives]]

### Screenshots

&lt;gallery&gt;
File:Demo1.png|Several demo quests are included to help you learn how to write quests for PMQ.
File:Demo2.png|You can play these demo quests directly, or you can save a copy to your Drafts and make some changes, then try it out!
File:Draft1.png|Write your own quests in game with just a few lines of script. You can even share your quests with other PMQ users in your party with just the click of a button!
File:Questlog1.png|Quest objectives are tracked and updated in real-time as you complete them.
&lt;/gallery&gt;</text>
      <sha1>ndnz4wctwd0oil9au1z57gxcff0cc5n</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Recipient</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>98</id>
    <revision>
      <id>224</id>
      <timestamp>2020-12-01T02:27:04Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Created page with "The **recipient** parameter allows you to specify the name of a player which must receive an objective in order for it to be completed.  ### Value type  * String - the p..."</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1205">The **recipient** parameter allows you to specify the name of a player which must receive an objective in order for it to be completed.

### Value type

* String - the player character's name. This should be the character's name only, do not include their realm.

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[say]]
| The player character(s) which you must whisper in order to complete the objective
|}

### Usage notes

* Player names are case-sensitive, so make sure you capitalize the first letter of the player's name!
* You do not need to specify &lt;code&gt;channel: whisper&lt;/code&gt; on a [[Say]] objective if you specify a recipient. Since whispers are the only channel that are targeted toward a specific player, the whisper channel is implied by specifying a recipient.
* You can specify multiple recipients, which means that interacting with *any one* of these recipients will satisfy the objective. For example:

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - say:
      message: "wash yer back"
      recipient: [ Playerone, Playertwo ] # You can message either Playerone or Playertwo to complete this objective
}}

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>5bh9453fp0wnmt7c0axwf78k6hddje8</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Requirements</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>11</id>
    <revision>
      <id>278</id>
      <parentid>65</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-07-24T18:41:11Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1386">[[File:Requirements.png|thumb|300px|Example of how quest requirements are rendered]]
[[File:RecommendedWarning.png|thumb|300px|Warning if a player chooses to accept a quest which they don't meet the **recommendations** for]]

By default, quests written in PMQ can be started by any player character without restriction. However, you may want to place some restrictions on who is able to take on your quest. PMQ supports this through the **recommended** and **required** properties on a quest.

{{code-yaml|c=
required:
  class: Mage
recommended:
  level: 30
  faction: Horde
}}

### What's the difference?

Both of these properties support all the same parameters and are evaluated in the same way. The only difference is in how they are presented to players when they attempt to start your quest.

* **required** - Players will not be allowed to start your quest if they do not meet the required parameters.
* **recommended** - Players will be prompted with an additional warning dialog when they try to start a quest without the recommended parameters, during which they can choose to start the quest anyway.

### Supported parameters

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Parameter
! How it's used
|-
| [[class]]
| The name of the class allowed to start this quest
|-
| [[faction]]
| Either "Horde" or "Alliance"
|-
| [[level]]
| The minimum level to start the quest
|}</text>
      <sha1>m34zswcqcg38kymtbgl4kyzvoy144j1</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Rewards</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>99</id>
    <revision>
      <id>250</id>
      <parentid>247</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-01-01T00:58:26Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="5567">[[File:Rewards-menu.PNG|thumb|300px|The Quest Rewards menu, and rewards as shown upon completion of a quest.]]
[[File:Quest-verification-menu.PNG|thumb|300px|The Quest Verification menu, which can be accessed for any quest in your Quest Log.]]

As an option to make your quests more enticing to players, you can specify **rewards** that will be given to players on quest completion. These rewards can take the form of money or items.

The rewards are not generated by PMQ - of course, addons can't simply generate items out of thin air! However, the player will be notified that they can contact a certain player (or group of players) and trade them in order to receive their quest rewards. In addition, PMQ will track which rewards a player is eligible for, and reward-givers will be able to verify that players have actually completed a quest, along with which rewards players are eligible for.

### How it works

=### Claiming Rewards=

When you complete a quest that offers rewards, you will see the rewards listed below the completion text for a quest. If the quest asks you to choose a reward, you will need to click one of the items before you're able to complete the quest.

After completing the quest, you can visit the **Quest Rewards** menu (part of the PMQ main menu) anytime to see which rewards you're eligible for, and which players you can claim them from. The players providing the rewards *may not have been notified* that you completed the quest, so you may need to message them and ask about receiving your rewards. This menu exists to help you keep track of which rewards you've earned and will not have any impact on your ability to perform other quests, so you can delete items from the list at any time.

If a reward-giver trades you an item or an amount of money that you're eligible for, then that reward will automatically be marked as "Traded" from that player. However, you can manually mark any reward as "Claimed" by selecting it in the list and clicking **Mark Claimed**. You may want to do this if you got the reward in a trade from a different player than who was listed, or if you received your reward in the mail (mail support may be added in a future update).

=### Distributing Rewards=

As a reward-giver, you can verify that a player has completed that quest, as well as see which item rewards they're eligible for. Open the **Quest Log** menu and select the quest you want to verify completion for, then click the **Verify Others** option.

From the Quest Verification menu, you'll be able to verify that either the targeted player, the players in your party, or the players in your raid group have completed a quest. Note that *anyone* can perform verification for any quest, whether or not they shared the quest, and whether or not the quest has rewards.

However, if a quest has rewards and you're a reward-giver for that quest, then the items and money that each player is eligible for will be linked in your chat window. This allows you to quickly scan a group of players for rewards without needing to message each player individually.

### Syntax

{{code-yaml|c=
rewards:
  player: Playername # Required
  money: 2g 46s 13c
  choose: true
  item:
    - 5 Major Mana Potion
    - 20 Major Healing Potion
    - 10 Greater Nature Protection Potion
}}

* You must specify either **money** or at least one **item** in your rewards.
* If you specify **choose: true**, then you must specify at least 2 **item** rewards.

### Supported parameters

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Parameter
! How it's used
|-
| **player**
| The player(s) who are responsible for giving out the rewards.&lt;br/&gt;You may also use the variables **%author** and **%giver** instead of a player's name.
|-
| **money**
| The amount of money awarded for completing the quest.&lt;br/&gt;This can be written as an amount of copper (such as: 24153) or a string with g/s/c (such as: 2g 41s 53c)
|-
| **choose**
| Set to **true** if the player should choose only *one item* from the list.&lt;br/&gt;Otherwise, it's implied that the player will receive *all* of the listed rewards.
|-
| [[Item (Rewards)|item]]
| The item(s) awarded for completing the quest.
|}

### Examples

=### Multiple reward givers=

You can specify multiple players who are responsible for giving out the rewards on a quest. If a player trades with any of players listed on the quest, then that trade can count towards the player claiming the quest's reward.

{{code-yaml|c=
rewards:
  player: [ Playerone, Playertwo, Playerthree ]
  money: 5g
}}

=### Quest giver as the reward giver=

If you specify **%giver** as the player under rewards, then the person who shares the quest will always be responsible for distributing the reward. This way, you can write a quest that provides rewards but doesn't necessarily have to relate back to a specific player or group of players.

{{code-yaml|c=
rewards:
  player: %giver
  money: 5g
}}

If you would like, you can also specify **%author** as the reward giver, and the person who originally drafted the quest will always be responsible for distributing rewards.

{{code-yaml|c=
rewards:
  player: %author
  money: 5g
}}

=### Single/Multiple item rewards=

See [[Item (Rewards)]] for examples of how to define reward items.

### Usage Notes

* In order to specify a valid game item by name, you must have encountered it in-game at some point during your current play session. For more information about this behavior and how you can work around it, see [[Item (Rewards)]].</text>
      <sha1>fu5qdekdio7vkm7tuc30ffi15wy9jpe</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Save Data &amp; Cache</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>113</id>
    <revision>
      <id>296</id>
      <parentid>292</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-07-24T21:18:06Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="5462">The **Save Data &amp; Cache** menu allows you to manage various pieces of save data that PMQ generates while you use the addon.

### Overview

[[File:SaveDataMenu.png|thumb|300px|The Save Data &amp; Cache menu screen]]

The World of Warcraft API is very selective about some of the information that it makes available to addons. Because of this, it's difficult to answer some questions that PMQ needs to ask when determining whether or not the player has just completed a quest objective. For example, these questions cannot be answered strictly through the WoW API:

* You just killed a "Stonetusk Boar". What level was it?
* You just cast Frostbolt on a player named "Questborther". What guild were they in?

To work around this, PMQ **caches**, or stores a copy of, data about the game world whenever it becomes available through the API. This way, PMQ can take a "best guess" at answering questions like these anytime the addon needs to do so, such as during quest objective completion. PMQ might answer the above questions like this:

* You targeted a monster named "Stonetusk Boar" earlier, and it was Level 5.
* You grouped with a player named "Questborther" a couple of days ago, and they were in the guild &lt;code&gt;&lt;Pals for Life&gt;&lt;/code&gt;.

Cached data is shared across **all characters** on your Battle.net account.

### Player Data Cache

PMQ caches data about other players whenever you target a player, mouseover a player, or join a party or raid group. Any player that you have "seen" in one of these ways should be an eligible target for quest objective completion. For example, in order to get credit for killing a level 30+ player, you must have targeted, moused over, or grouped with that player at some point, so PMQ can know what level they were before you killed them. With that in mind, there are some edge cases to watch out for:

* You may not get credit for kills made by other members in your party if you have never "seen" the target that they killed
* You may not get credit for kills or spellcasts performed with AOE spells, if you happen to have never moused over the target.
* Targets with level "??"/"Skull" may not count towards objectives with a [[level]] condition, because WoW does not make the target's true level available to addons

If you think you should have gotten credit for a kill, try confirming the target's info with **Print All**, and let us know in Discord if it's not working like you'd expect.

Menu options:

* **Print All**: Prints all cached player data to your chat window, including the name, guild, faction, level, sex, and race for each player you've seen. If your cache is large, then you may not see all entries in the chat window.
* **Delete All**: Deletes all cached information about players that you've seen.

### NPC Data Cache

PMQ caches data about NPCs whenever you target or mouseover them. The same rules that applies to Player data also apply to NPCs, with the exception that some data points are exclusive to players and unavailable (or not reliable) from NPCs (such as class, race, sex, or guild).

If you think you should have gotten credit for a kill, try confirming the target's info with **Print All**, and let us know in Discord if it's not working like you'd expect.

Menu options:

* **Print All**: Prints all cached NPC data to your chat window, including the name, faction, and level range for each NPC you've seen. If your cache is large, then you may not see all entries in the chat window.
* **Delete All**: Deletes all cached information about NPCs that you've seen.

### Item Data Cache

Menu options:

* **Search**: Provide any item name or ID in the search field. If the item is found in your cache, it will be linked to you in the chat window.
* **Begin Scan**: Starts looking for valid item IDs from 1 to 184K, and caches any item information found with those IDs. This scan takes around **20-30 minutes** and should find just under 30K items in TBC. You can let this run in the background while you play, but encountering any loading screen may interrupt the scan.
* **Delete All**: Deletes all item information in the cache. You'll need to scan again to restore a full database of items.

### Spell Data Cache

Menu options:

* **Search**: Provide any spell name or ID in the search field. If the spell is found in your cache, then the spell's name and ID will printed in the chat window.
* **Begin Scan**: Starts looking for valid spell IDs from 1 to 50K, and caches any spell information found with those IDs. This scan takes around **2-3 minutes** and should find around 15K spells in TBC. You can let this run in the background while you play, but encountering any loading screen may interrupt the scan.
* **Delete All**: Deletes all spell information in the cache. You'll need to scan again to restore a full database of spells.

### Other Menu Options

* **Reset Frame Positions**: This will delete the saved position of any popout menus within PMQ (such as the Quest Log or Location Finder). Menus should immediately return to their default positions when this is run. Click this if you ever lose a popout menu by accidentally dragging it off screen.
* **Reset All Save Data**: This will delete all of the save data managed by PMQ, including data caches, frame positions, as well as **quest drafts and quest completions**. Use this as an absolute last resort in case your PMQ save data gets somehow corrupted.</text>
      <sha1>0ggmu86iwqcushvfggkbrjvmn2wmt6n</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Say</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>91</id>
    <revision>
      <id>234</id>
      <parentid>233</parentid>
      <timestamp>2020-12-01T04:26:39Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="3217">The **say** objective is triggered whenever you send a message to a chat channel. This objective requires you to send a message that meets a message containing a certain phrase, along with meeting any of the conditions outlined below.

### Shorthand

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - say "message*"
}}

*&lt;nowiki&gt;*required&lt;/nowiki&gt;*

Note that this shorthand form is not recommended for real quest objectives, only for quickly testing phrases. Use the long form better quest objectives.

### Long form

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - say:
      message: "my secret message" # Required. Quotes are optional, but recommended.
      language: Dwarvish
      channel: yell
      target: Questborther # A player's name to whisper
      zone: Elwynn Forest
      subzone: Goldshire
      coords: 42.41, 64.47, 0.3
      aura: "Power Word: Fortitude"
      equip: Loose Chain Mail
      item: Light Leather
      text: "Custom display text"
}}

### Supported parameters

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Parameter
! How it's used
|-
| [[aura]]
| The name of the aura you must have when saying the message
|-
| [[channel]]
| The channel(s) you must say the message through (see linked page for options)
|-
| [[equip]]
| An item you must have equipped when saying the message
|-
| [[item]]
| An item you must have in your bags when saying the message
|-
| [[language]]
| The RP language(s) that the message must be spoken in
|-
| [[message]]
| The phrase or pattern that must be present within the message
|-
| [[recipient]]
| The name of the player(s) you must send the message to (only applicable to whispers)
|-
| [[Display Text|text]]
| Custom display text for this objective
|-
| [[zone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[zone|subzone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[coords]]
| The location you must be in when saying the message
|}

### Examples

=### Secret messages=

You will likely want to change the default display text of the objective so that it doesn't reveal the exact text that the player should speak in order to progress. Consider the following example:

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - say:
      text: "Speak, friend, and enter."
      message: "mellon"
      channel: [ say, yell ]
      zone: Moria
      subzone: Doors of Durin
      coords: 38.7, 42.5, 0.1
}}

In this hypothetical example, the player would need to /say or /yell a message with the phrase "mellon", while standing in front of the Doors of Durin, in order to progress the quest objective. However, the quest log would simply read the riddle: "Speak, friend, and enter."

Note that this will print the same text to the quest log, quest info frame, and quest progress message (the yellow text that pops up when you progress). See the [[Display text]] page for details on how to configure these individually.

Here's another take on this old classic:

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - say:
      text: "Speak, friend, and enter."
      message: "^friend$"
      language: Dwarvish
      channel: [ say, yell ]
}}

In this example, the player would need to /say or /yell exactly the word "friend" (see the) while speaking in the Dwarvish [[language]] in-game. Saying "friend" in Common or any other language would not complete the objective.

[[Category:Quest Objectives]]</text>
      <sha1>8o7zqjqeaez2p1vdpfmikhf0cm4d65r</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Spell</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>106</id>
    <revision>
      <id>259</id>
      <parentid>258</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-01-23T20:47:23Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="4105">The **spell** parameter lets you specify which spell(s) must be cast in order to complete an objective.

### Value type

* String - The name of the spell (case-insensitive)
* Number - The ID of the spell

Note that regardless of whether you specify the name or ID of a spell in your quests, **all spells with the same name** will count towards objective completion. For example, whether you use name "Frostbolt" or the number [https://classic.wowhead.com/spell=7322/frostbolt 7322] as the spell in your quest, all ranks of Frostbolt will count towards objectives.

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  # Both of the following will support any rank of Frostbolt being cast
  - cast-spell:
      spell: frostbolt
  - cast-spell:
      spell: 7322
}}

See the guide below for more info on how to get spells by name to use in your quests.

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[cast-spell]]
| The spell you must cast
|}

### Getting spells by name

PMQ requires you to provide valid in-game spells in all your quests; your quests will fail validation if any spell names or IDs cannot be found in-game. If you use valid spell IDs (numbers), then you should encounter no problems with looking up your spells. However, the WoW API has a peculiar limitation: you can only get spells by *name* if that spell is **in your current spellbook**. For example, if you try to reference the spell "Blessing of Might" by name while on a Hunter, the WoW API will tell you that this spell does not exist.

Fortunately, PMQ offers some solutions to work around this limitation so that you can reference any spells by name on any character.

* You can search for the spell on [https://classic.wowhead.com/ Wowhead] and grab the spell's ID from the URL, such as &lt;code&gt;spell=1234&lt;/code&gt;, where 1234 is the ID. Then, do one of two things:
** Use the spell by ID in your quest, following the examples above. Keep in mind that **any spell with the same name** will count towards your objective, so you don't need to worry about getting the ID of a specific rank of a spell. Any rank will work.
** You can also use the chat command &lt;code&gt;/pmq lookup-spell 1234&lt;/code&gt;, where 1234 is your spell ID. PMQ will now remember that spell's name and you can reference it by name in your quests.
* If you want to avoid this problem in the future, run the command &lt;code&gt;/pmq scan-spells&lt;/code&gt;. This kicks off a process that will check for **every known spell in the game** and cache their names for future use in any quest draft on any character.
** This process only takes about 2-3 minutes to run and may have a small effect on your game's performance while it's running. See [[Configuration]] for info on how to configure this scan.

Finally, you can erase all cached spell names from PMQ with the chat command &lt;code&gt;/pmq clear-spells&lt;/code&gt;.

### Discovering spells

[[File:SpellWatch.PNG|thumb|Toggle this feature on or off with: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;/pmq watch-spells&lt;/code&gt;]]

Many actions that your character performs in game are considered "spells" for the sake of gameplay and will work with this quest condition. Beyond your spellbook, things like Skinning, [https://classic.wowhead.com/spell=18517/pattern-mooncloth-bag learning patterns], or using your [https://classic.wowhead.com/spell=8690/hearthstone Hearthstone] are all considered spell casts.

Since it can be difficult to figure out exactly which spells you should put in your quests, PMQ provides a **spell-watching tool** that you can activate with the chat command &lt;code&gt;/pmq watch-spells&lt;/code&gt;. When enabled, this will print a message containing the spell name, spell ID, and (if applicable) target name for every successful spell that your character casts. Simply enable scanning and then perform whatever action(s) you want to be part of your quest, and take note of the spells that it reports.

Spell watching only lasts for the current session and is turned off whenever you /reload or log out. To disable it yourself, simply enter the chat command again.

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>hliik3ok2ew5qkhwilc2kji2i64edpy</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Start &amp; Complete Objectives</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>12</id>
    <revision>
      <id>236</id>
      <parentid>74</parentid>
      <timestamp>2020-12-31T22:21:49Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>Update table class</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="2239">[[File:startcomplete1.png|thumb|300px|Quest **description** text and **start** block rendered as quest info]]
[[File:startcomplete2.png|thumb|300px|Quest **completion** text and **complete** block rendered as quest info]]

By default, quests written in PMQ can be started anywhere in the world at any time, simply by selecting the quest from the catalog or by being invited from another player. Similarly, quests can be completed from anywhere by simply opening the quest once all objectives are completed and clicking "Complete Quest".

But quests in WoW generally don't operate this way - you're usually required to talk to an NPC or interact with an object in order to start or complete a quest. To support this flow of gameplay, PMQ provides the **start** and **complete** conditions for quests.

{{code-yaml|c=
start:
  zone: Elwynn Forest
  target: Marshal Dughan
complete:
  zone: Lion's Pride Inn
  target: Innkeeper Farley
}}

### What's the difference?

Both properties support all the same parameters and are evaluated in the same way. The only difference is when they're evaluated during a quest.

* **start** - What conditions are required before the player can accept the quest (click the "Accept" button)?
* **complete** - What conditions are required in order for the player to turn in the quest (click the "Complete Quest" button)?

### Supported parameters

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Parameter
! How it's used
|-
| [[coords]]
| The coordinates you must be at in order to start or complete the quest
|-
| [[target]]
| The NPC that must be targeted in order to start or complete the quest
|-
| [[Display Text|text]]
| Custom display text for the start or complete condition
|-
| [[zone|zone&lt;br/&gt;subzone]]
| The name of the zone and/or subzone where the quest starts or ends
|}

### [[Display Text]] variables

{| class="wikitable"
! Variable
! Parameter
|-
| **%t**
| target
|-
| **%z**
| zone
|-
| **%sz**
| subzone
|-
| **%co**
| coords
|-
| **%x**
| x-coordinate of coords
|-
| **%y**
| y-coordinate of coords
|-
| **%r**
| radius of coords
|-
| **%xy**
| coords formatted as: &lt;code&gt;(x, y)&lt;/code&gt;
|-
| **%xyr**
| coords formatted as: &lt;code&gt;(x, y) +/- radius&lt;/code&gt;
|}</text>
      <sha1>6ighyhcol4qtic42bwguavg0ltjtf8d</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Talk-to</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>24</id>
    <revision>
      <id>145</id>
      <parentid>137</parentid>
      <timestamp>2020-08-24T00:41:32Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1783">The **talk-to** objective is triggered whenever you talk to an NPC, which includes opening their gossip frame, shop window, stable window, or any other window that causes the NPC to face you.

If your goal is to talk to more than 1 of a target NPC, you must talk to different instances of that NPC (e.g. 3 different "Stormwind Guard" NPCs) in order to complete the objective.

In case you cannot talk to the target NPC in game (for example, if you've finished all of their quests and they no longer have any dialogue), then PMQ allows you to use the **/talk** emote on the NPC in order to progress this objective. You must be near the NPC (within approximately 10 yards) in order for this to work.

### Shorthand

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - talk-to goal "target*"
}}

*&lt;nowiki&gt;*required&lt;/nowiki&gt;*

### Long form

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - talk-to:
      target: "Stormwind Guard" # Required
      goal: 3
      zone: Elwynn Forest
      subzone: Goldshire
      coords: 42.41, 64.47, 0.3
      aura: "Power Word: Fortitude"
      equip: Loose Chain Mail
      item: Light Leather
      text: "Custom display text"
}}

### Supported parameters

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Parameter
! How it's used
|-
| [[aura]]
| The name of the aura you must have when talking to the target
|-
| [[equip]]
| An item you must have equipped when talking to the target
|-
| [[goal]]
| The number of times you must talk to the target
|-
| [[item]]
| An item you must have in your bags when talking to the target
|-
| [[target]]
| The name of the NPC to talk to
|-
| [[Display Text|text]]
| Custom display text for this objective
|-
| [[zone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[zone|subzone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[coords]]
| The location you must be in when talking to this target
|}

[[Category:Quest Objectives]]</text>
      <sha1>3isoex7zlwogqzjox6ssttpxqr70dzw</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Target</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>17</id>
    <revision>
      <id>262</id>
      <parentid>135</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-02-06T19:12:55Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>100.7.77.237</ip>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1768">The **target** parameter is used in a variety of ways, but in general it is used to specify the monster, NPC, or player that must be targeted in order to progress an objective.

### Value type

* String - the name of the monster or NPC as it appears in-game

### Supported objectives

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[cast-spell]]
| The target that you must cast a spell on
|-
| [[kill]]
| The target that must be killed
|-
| [[talk-to]]
| The target that must be talked to
|-
| [[use-emote]]
| The target which the emote must be used on
|}

This parameter can also be used as a [[Start &amp; Complete Objectives|start or complete condition]].

### Unique Targets

For objectives requiring you to act on the same target multiple times (i.e. with a goal &gt; 1), you must target "unique instances" of a monster or NPC in order to progress the objective. However, this unique-target restriction **does not apply to players**. Consider the following example:

* &lt;code&gt;use-emote salute 5 "Stormwind Guard"&lt;/code&gt; - You must salute 5 _different_ Stormwind Guards to complete this objective.
* &lt;code&gt;use-emote salute 5 Questborther&lt;/code&gt; - Assuming Questborther is a player's name, you can salute that same player 5 times to complete this objective.

### Usage notes

* The target's name must be spelled and capitalized exactly as it is in-game in order for the objective to progress.
* Currently, there is no localization implemented in the addon, so players using a client in a different language (where the target has a different name) will not be able to progress the objective. The initial release of PMQ is targeting English-language clients only, with localization to come later.

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>l7agib5fde2nuaaq4cd3dpt8vywef0b</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Use-emote</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>20</id>
    <revision>
      <id>271</id>
      <parentid>146</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-07-24T18:14:16Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1945">The **use-emote** objective is triggered whenever you use an emote, such as &lt;code&gt;/dance&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;/glare&lt;/code&gt;. This objective cannot be triggered by custom emotes sent with the &lt;code&gt;/e&lt;/code&gt; command.

If your goal is to use an emote more than 1 time on a target NPC, you must use the emote on different instances of that NPC (e.g. 3 different "Stormwind Guard" NPCs) in order to complete the objective.

### Shorthand

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - use-emote "emote*" goal "target"
}}

*&lt;nowiki&gt;*required&lt;/nowiki&gt;*

### Long form

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - use-emote:
      goal: 3
      emote: dance # Required
      target: "Stormwind Guard"
      level: 30
      guild: Pals for Life
      class: Mage
      faction: Alliance
      zone: Elwynn Forest
      subzone: Goldshire
      coords: 42.41, 64.47, 0.3
      aura: "Power Word: Fortitude"
      equip: Loose Chain Mail
      item: Light Leather
      text: "Custom display text"
}}

### Supported parameters

{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Parameter
! How it's used
|-
| [[aura]]
| The name of the aura you must have when using the emote
|-
| [[class]]
| The emote target must be a player of this class
|-
| [[emote]]
| The name of the emote you must use
|-
| [[equip]]
| An item you must have equipped when using the emote
|-
| [[faction]]
| The emote target must be a player or NPC of this faction (Alliance or Horde)
|-
| [[goal]]
| The number of times you must use the emote
|-
| [[guild]]
| The emote target must be a player in this guild
|-
| [[item]]
| An item you must have in your bags when using the emote
|-
| [[level]]
| The emote target must be this level or higher
|-
| [[target]]
| The name of the monster or NPC to use the emote on
|-
| [[Display Text|text]]
| Custom display text for this objective
|-
| [[zone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[zone|subzone]]&lt;br/&gt;[[coords]]
| The location you must be in when using the emote
|}

[[Category:Quest Objectives]]</text>
      <sha1>007jlyzy8juehuuvni5n10pe2fe3u5l</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>YAML</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>13</id>
    <revision>
      <id>108</id>
      <parentid>104</parentid>
      <timestamp>2020-08-12T00:58:52Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Dolphinspired</username>
        <id>3</id>
      </contributor>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="4439">**YAML** (which stands for "YAML Ain't Markup Language" - yes, really) is a simple language intended for writing configuration files that can be easily read and understood by humans, but also easily parsed by computers. This guide will give you a brief rundown on everything you need to know about YAML to write quests in PMQ.

### Properties and values

{{code-yaml|c=
name: Ragnaros    # this is a string - a line of text
level: 63         # this is a number - can also include decimals
spicy: true       # this is a boolean - can be true or false
}}

In this example, we have a simple YAML document with 3 properties: &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;level&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;spicy&lt;/code&gt; - each with a value assigned.

In addition, everything after a &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; character is a comment, which means it will not be interpreted as YAML. I've added some comments explaining what type each value is.

### String quotation

When writing out simple string values in YAML, quotes are generally optional. The following values will all be interpreted in the same way:

{{code-yaml|c=
target: Murloc Steamrunner   # Will print as: Murloc Steamrunner
zone: "Elwynn Forest"        # Will print as: Elwynn Forest
subzone: 'Crystal Lake'      # Will print as: Crystal lake
}}

However, if you are using any YAML special characters in your string, then you *must* include quotes. Either single or double quotes are fine.

{{code-yaml|c=
name: Lesson 1: Tutorial     # BAD! YAML gets confused by the extra colon
name: "Lesson 1: Tutorial"   # Easy fix
name: 'Lesson 1: Tutorial'   # Also fine
}}

PMQ also includes a special rule for writing shorthand quest [[objective|objectives]]. When you are writing strings that contain multiple words, you *must* include quotes in order to group these words together.

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - kill 5 Mangy Wolf        # BAD! Gets broken into 3 parameters: 5, Mangy, and Wolf
  - kill 5 "Mangy Wolf"      # Gets broken into 2 parameters: 5 and Mangy Wolf
}}

When in doubt, include quotes anyway!

### Long strings

[[File:line-break-before.png|thumb|300px|Before line breaks are added]]
[[File:line-break-after.png|thumb|300px|After line breaks are added with %br]]

You can spread a long string over multiple lines by prefixing it with the &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; character, like this:

{{code-yaml|c=
quest:
  description: &gt;
    Get up on the floor
    Dancin' all night long
    Get up on the floor
    Dancin' till the break of dawn
}}

However, the above example will still print out as one long line when displayed in game. For cases like this, PMQ allows you to insert line breaks using the special escape code &lt;code&gt;%br&lt;/code&gt;.

{{code-yaml|c=
quest:
  description: &gt;
    Get up on the floor%br
    Dancin' all night long%br
    Get up on the floor%br
    Dancin' till the break of dawn
}}

### Block indentation

{{code-yaml|c=
name: Malfurion
pet: # the "pet" block has 4 properties
  name: Tricky
  species: Raptor
  colors: # the "colors" block has 2 properties
    hide: red
    feathers: green
  level: 35
# Simple blocks can also be written on one line (flow-style)
pet: { name: Tricky, species: Raptor, level: 35 }
}}

You can nest properties inside other properties to form a block. This is achieved by simply indenting a line more. It doesn't matter how much you indent the line, as long as you are consistent throughout your YAML document. We recommend indenting with 2 or 4 spaces per level.

### Sequences

{{code-yaml|c=
name: Malfurion
# Sequence with one item per line
pets:
  - Tricky
  - Beedle
  - Midna
# Sequence with all items on one line (flow-style)
pets: [ Tricky, Beedle, Midna ]
}}

You can assign multiple values to a property by adding a &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; before each value. Each item in a sequence can be a simple type (string, number, or boolean) or another block of properties, which you will see when writing quest objectives:

{{code-yaml|c=
objectives:
  - kill 5 Chicken
  - explore:
      zone: Elwynn Forest
      subzone: Goldshire
}}

### More information

* [https://cheat.readthedocs.io/en/latest/yaml.html YAML cheatsheet] - a short cheatsheet with just the basics of YAML.
* [https://github.com/peposso/lua-tinyyaml lua-tinyyaml] - the YAML parser library used in PMQ. Not all features of YAML are supported by this library, so you may want to poke around here if you're trying to use more advanced YAML features and they're not working.</text>
      <sha1>7i058yxssepeaud1s1pxslm1jbndf3z</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Zone</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>19</id>
    <revision>
      <id>268</id>
      <parentid>229</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-02-06T19:22:49Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>100.7.77.237</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Supported objectives */</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1621">The **zone** and **subzone** parameters are used to specify the names of in-game areas where an objective must be completed.

### Value type

* String - the name of a zone or subzone as it appears in-game

### Supported objectives
{| class="wikitable boldlinks"
! Objective
! How it's used
|-
| [[cast-spell]]
| The zone where you must be when casting the spell
|-
| [[equip-item]]
| The zone where you must be when equipping the item
|-
| [[explore]]
| The zone where you must be in order to complete the objective
|-
| [[gain-aura]]
| The zone where you must gain the aura
|-
| [[kill]]
| The zone where you must kill the target
|-
| [[loot-item]]
| The zone where you must loot the item
|-
| [[say]]
| The zone you must be in when saying the message
|-
| [[talk-to]]
| The zone where you must talk to the target
|-
| [[use-emote]]
| The zone where you must use the emote
|}

This parameter can also be used as a [[Start &amp; Complete Objectives|start or complete condition]].

### Usage notes

* Zone and subzone are completely interchangeable - both parameters will look at both your current zone and subzone for a match when evaluating objectives.
* The zone's name must be spelled and capitalized exactly as it is in-game in order for the objective to progress.
* Currently, there is no localization implemented in the addon, so players using a client in a different language (where the zone has a different name) will not be able to progress the objective. The initial release of PMQ is targeting English-language clients only, with localization to come later.

[[Category:Quest Objective Parameters]]</text>
      <sha1>f92h389mqtz48fcf6pvf74vnsxev0kn</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
